<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homes on My New Hugo Site</title><link>http://example.org/home/</link><description>Recent content in Homes on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/work/</guid><description>Work Experience At a glance&amp;hellip;
Apple SPG Embedded Controls Software Intern May-Aug 2022 Apple SPG Embedded Controls Software Intern Jan-Aug 2021 Indico AI Backend Software Intern May-Aug 2020 Yay Brigade Full-stack Software Intern Jan-Aug 2019 More details 🔽
Apple SPG Embedded Controls Software Intern | May-Aug 2022, Jan-Aug 2021
I spent the last two summers (as well as a semester off from school) as an embedded controls software intern at Apple in the Special Projects Group in Sunnyvale, California.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/formula/formula/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/formula/formula/</guid><description>At Olin, I&amp;rsquo;m a member of Olin Electric Motorsports, our Formula SAE electric race car team.
I work on firmware, mostly for high voltage systems and tooling infrastructure.
navigate down to learn more
🔽
Year 1 As a first-year on the electrical subteam, I designed, fabricated, and tested a PCB called the Brake System Plausibility Device, or BSPD.
This is a safety-critical board that will shutdown the car if power is being delivered to the motor while the brake pedal is pressed for longer than half a second.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/</guid><description> Here are some projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on&amp;hellip; Electrical SCOPE PCB.
Firmware 4KB CAN Bootloader. MKV BMS. AIR Control.
Software The Gauntlet.
To go back to the first slide, just press `Shift` ←</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/scope-pcb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/scope-pcb/</guid><description>SCOPE PCB PCB for a single-watt scale electrical generator.
Partially redacted due to NDA. navigate down to learn more
🔽
For my senior capstone (SCOPE), I worked with a company to develop a single-watt scale electrical generator. The motor is driven externally and the microcontroller (STM32F3) uses PWM commutation to control the motor driver to generate the optimal amount of energy to reduce startup torque.
On board, there is a motor driver IC, a battery charging IC and battery management system, a 5V buck converter, and a microcontroller.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/can-bootloader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/can-bootloader/</guid><description>CAN Bootloader A bootloader that can reprogram chips using CAN.
Code repository. Documentation.
navigate down to learn more
🔽
Historically, on our Formula team, whenever we wanted to update the firmware on our circuit boards, we had to use an in-system programming (ISP) dongle and plug into each board manually.
This often meant opening up enclosures, and required us to have a large programming header on each board, adding height and exposed copper.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/air_control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/air_control/</guid><description>AIR Control High-voltage power distribution for an EV.
Code repository. Documentation.
navigate down to learn more
🔽
In an electric vehicle, we need to safely connect our high voltage battery and motor controller. However, connecting it directly is dangerous for the system—we can end up with a massive surge of current and potentially weld our contactors shut.
On our Formula team, I rewrote the firmware for the contactor control system (which we call AIR Control 1).</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/bms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/bms/</guid><description>MKV BMS A battery management system for a 400V EV battery.
Code repository. Documentation.
navigate down to learn more
🔽
For the Olin Electric Motorsports MKV vehicle, we had a 400V battery pack built with 864 18650 lithium-ion batteries. In order to ensure safe operation, we built a custom BMS. A few of my teammates worked on the electrical systems and PCBs, and I wrote the firmware.
The BMS core uses isoSPI to communicate with peripheral boards, each containing two LTC6811 battery management integrated chips.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/gauntlet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/gauntlet/</guid><description>The Gauntlet Gradient descent algorithm simulated for a
differential-drive robot.
navigate down to learn more
🔽
For my Quantitative Engineering Analysis course (sophomore year), the goal of the final project was to navigate a simulated Roomba-like robot through a world called The Gauntlet, avoiding obstacles (boxes) until finally reaching the goal (cylinder).
The robot was equiped with a LIDAR camera that sampled points around it. I used a random sample consensus (RANSAC) algorithm to organize the individual points from LIDAR into a series of lines and a circle (the goal).</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/contact/</guid><description>Contact Resume.
Email: j@jackgreenberg.co
Github: @jack-greenberg
Twitter: @jackgreenb
To go back to the first slide, just press Shift ←</description></item><item><title/><link>http://example.org/home/projects/contactor-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/home/projects/contactor-control/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>